Oh
So that's your Ryu. I know this might sound rude, but what do you see in that guy?
Well, he and I used to be neighbors until my family moved away back in fourth grade
Out of the way beanstalk don't stand in the doorway large
Any birds land on your head this morning
It's a knuckle sandwich
Listen it's cool to be tall so you should stand up straight and be proud of it
Right today. I'm gonna take you to the best place ever
Ryo no skate. I told you that is not how we enter a room
I
Don't really know how to explain it, but I guess him doing that helped me to be a little more confident, right?
Yeah
Oh stop it. I didn't say anything. I'm just picking up on your vibe
I
Can I walk you home?
I'm fine
Allow me
No, you go to practice
I don't think I've ever had a real chance before in my life
But now I do have a chance
So I wonder if that means
If this is the moment, I'm finally a man
Would you please pull yourself together? You've been a dude for years
This is your fault, Inoshita
If you say so
You don't know
Let the three
I
We'll be right back.
All right, now we can start talking about tomorrow.
So look, nothing I say will change this, so I'm just going to rip the band-aid off.
We're up against the team that got second place in this year's Inter High.
Inarizaki High School, representing Hyogo.
And, well, you might say they're the favorites to win the entire championship.
First, their top scorer, number four, Alan Ojiro.
He's both very tall and very powerful.
And like Boguto from Fukurodani, he's one of the top three hitters in Japan.
In fact, when his defense is on, you can make a pretty good argument that he might be even better than that.
So just like when we faced Ushiwaka, you can't think of net defense and floor defense as two separate things.
We need to get him with our total defense.
Next up, their middle blocker, number 10, Rintaro Suna.
To be honest, he's actually on the shorter side for a middle blocker.
But the guys like Game Sense Incarnate.
Make sure you're constantly on him when he attacks.
He's guaranteed to get used to our quick attack, too.
So make sure to use a lot of space when you're on the offensive.
Mm-hmm.
Now, Ojiro and Suna are the two main guns.
But the real trouble is the one who makes brilliant use of those two and all their other spikers.
Their setter, Atsumu Mia.
You met him at the youth intensive, right, Kageyama?
Yes, sir.
That's the guy who's supposed to be the best high school setter in all of Japan.
He sets the ball in a way that makes the spiker believe he's better than he is.
He's that good.
And it's true, his sets are easy to hit.
They're consistent and always on target.
Even Kageyama admits he's good.
But unfortunately, his setting skills aren't the only thing we need to watch out for.
His serves.
Mm-hmm.
A little while ago, he started dual wielding.
He does spike serves and jump floaters.
So then we won't have any idea what he's going to do to us until the very last second.
Yeah, tough to pick the right receive formation like that.
And I heard he was given the best server award at both the inter-middle and inter-high tournaments.
I really did not need to hear that right now.
Mm-hmm.
Oh, sorry.
We just won a game, but they're already back to looking grim and serious.
The second seed.
Out of the dozens of teams listed here, we got stuck playing the second best one.
The top two teams in the country!
So that means that we'll get to play both of them!
Mm-hmm.
Yeah!
That only happens if the top seed Itachiyama actually makes it all the way to the finals,
since they're competing in the other block.
Well, yeah, of course.
But if someone beats Itachiyama, they'd be the new best team, right?
Oh, yeah.
Would they?
I can't with you two.
I just can't take it anymore.
Where do you guys get such bizarro confidence?
Oh, cold.
Okay, Asahi, you can do the thing now.
Huh?
The thing where you're all, well, it's our last high school tournament,
since I stopped you from saying it at the Inter High.
This isn't the time or place for that.
Sort of weird, though.
When you start to really stress out, somehow it gets a whole lot easier for me to stay calm.
What?
Shut up!
Huh?
Looks like our plucky, happy-go-lucky kids have finally run out of batteries.
Well, everything's been so different from the start of warm-ups.
It's possible that they pushed themselves too far and were more worn out than they were.
They realized we all need to make sure we don't hurt ourselves.
Yeah.
Damn it.
What the hell?
Am I nervous?
No.
This is just one of those things where I've got, like, adrenaline or something pumping through me.
You're gonna be fine.
Oh, Ryu!
Oh, hey, Kanaka!
How are you?
You've definitely got a chance there.
So, I guess it's pretty cold in Tokyo, too.
Yeah.
How's Saiko doing?
She's good.
What about your family?
Everything's fine.
They're doing well.
Ryu.
The thing is, I was wondering, wondering, wondering, wondering, wondering.
I'm sorry.
I already have my heart set on another.
What are you doing, Kanaka?
You should wait inside.
It's cold out here.
Kanaka.
Now a beautiful young woman.
The night skyline.
An older city boy.
I think, just maybe, I had the absolute wrong idea.
Pretend I never said anything!
Huh?
Wait!
Here.
My mother made you another one and sent it with me.
I think, uh, that I might have just gotten my heart broken.
Huh?
Uh, uh, there, there, it's...
Sorry, it's nothing.
Anyway, I didn't come here so I could fall in love.
Uh, alright.
I'm here to win a championship.
We're the second game.
We can practice on the court at 8 a.m. for 30 minutes.
Let's be quick.
Yes, sir!
Hey, excuse me.
Do you mind if we do spiking drills next?
Uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh, uh.
Is he the coach for Inarizaki? He oozes the aura of an experienced veteran.
We'd like to spend some more time serving!
If this Atsumumiya is such a super awesome setter, then we should probably aim for him when we return the ball, right?
Yeah, you're a genius, man!
Hang on now. The recording that we just watched was the finals match from their qualifier tournament.
From what I understand, their usual opposite hitter wasn't at 100%, so he set out the game.
Opposite hitter. Player opposite the setter. The same position that Daichi and Ushiwaka both play.
This time, there's a good chance that they will be using their usual opposite.
Oh, I get it now. Even if you manage to handle Atsumumiya, his twin brother will pick up the slack.
The most powerful duo in the high school volleyball scene. The Miya Twins.
So Inarizaki will be playing their first match today. How is the team doing?
Well, the first match can be rather scary and daunting for a team of any strength.
But I like to think we're all pretty calm. And everybody's in top shape now, so I'm feeling pretty good about things.
Can you tell me about your goals for the tournament?
Is that Machino, the sports reporter?
Well, the winner, of course.
Machino? What do we do if she tries to interview us, too? She might, you know?
Yeah, she only talks to the powerhouse schools. Don't get too worried about it. She'll leave us alone.
Oh, you think so?
Tadashi! Peace signs! Let's give him peace signs!
Huh? Don't.
Huh? He got mad at me!
Listen to me, okay? I'm serious. I'm telling you, you are way more of a catch than you seem to realize.
You're a damn Amazon!
It's not like this Ryu has a girlfriend or anything. You just gotta keep pushing!
Until he loses his mind.
But he...
Hey, what's wrong with you?
I can't get any serfs over the net.
And I just can't figure out how.
Hmm.
Mmm.
Oh!
If you try until you can, then you can't.
Huh?
Right!
Yeah, you're right.
I don't think she's necessarily understanding it the way I meant.
But whatever works.
Huh?
I'm so sorry for the weird thing I said to you last night. Please forget it happened.
No, no, it's fine. I'm sorry my brother interrupted.
What? I don't think I even knew you had a brother.
He's actually my cousin. He lives here.
Anytime I come to the city for a match, he'll usually bring me a good luck charm and food or something like that.
Well, he sounds like a great guy.
Wait.
But that means I was wrong about what made me think I was wrong, so...
So, um, I...
I don't slouch anymore.
Because of you.
And I'm really good now.
You should watch.
It's true.
Kanaka is really good now.
I'm the one who's getting left behind.
I am not gonna lose.
Hands, you dumbass!
I wanna jump right now!
Well, somebody's ready to go.
Oh, hello again.
It's been a minute. Have you been doing okay, Kageyama?
Fine, thanks.
That's him. Atsumumiya, right?
Be sure to do your best out there today.
There's absolutely nothing I hate more in the world than going up against crap players.
Power players are freaks.
Yeah, I'm sorry about that.
Darn it, Kageyama! Why would you apologize?
I promise I'm not a crap player.
Oh, yeah. I know that.
Unfortunately, he is, though.
What? How can you say that?
But he's not a weak player, so I'm pretty sure we'll be just fine.
Hmm.
Aha!
Dork.
The first match is in the middle of their second set.
Even in our alternate uniforms, Noya looks like the star of the show!
Right?
Kageyama, orange isn't really your color.
You shouldn't talk, you human tangerine.
What was that?
Huh?
It does feel weird, but what choice do we have?
The other team wears black, too.
With your hair, now you look even more ridiculous.
Ah!
Sukishima!
Sukishima, I really don't think you can talk, man!
Oh, man.
I wonder how those guys can stay so calm.
I mean, Hinata just doesn't really get nervous anymore.
I guess he gets so excited it's impossible to be scared.
I wish I had that.
Oh, actually, that reminds me.
I saw some girls holding fans with the Mia twins' names on them.
Are they pop stars or something?
Well, yeah, basically, that's exactly what he is.
But he's got a different kind of popularity than the champions,
because the way he plays the game keeps you on the edge of your seat.
When you put those things together, he's the ultimate challenger.
Come to think of it, I do see a lot of stories about him on TV.
Meanwhile, not a single person in this arena even knows that we exist.
What's wrong with you, Daichi?
Come on, get a grip, man!
It's great.
Looks like Daichi finally found his mojo.
We thought you seemed kind of reserved last night.
Come on, guys.
I was just concentrating.
Hey!
Let's head on out.
Right!
No!
Between you and me, that and Narizaki cheering section really pisses me off.
Remind me again, isn't Narizaki High known for its marching band, too?
My stomach!
Those giant trumpets are super cool!
I'm stomach!
Woo!
That is me!
The end!
Okay, let's go!
Let's go!
Yeah!
Nice kill, Suna.
Last one, boys.
Out-of-body delayed spike!
Well, that spike wasn't delayed.
He just wanted to sound cool.
Did the setter just spike the ball?
That was pretty dope.
I don't know.
The guy who made the set seem better.
Good job, guys!
Nice kill, Hinata!
Wow, man.
That kid got up there.
All right, the match between Narizaki High School, representing Hyogo Prefecture, and Karasuno
High School, representing Miyagi Prefecture, is about to begin!
Let's play!
All right!
It won't help anything if I'm freaking out.
Calm down!
Not a soul out there ever thought that Karasuno would beat Shira Torizawa.
So, guys, let's go out and surprise the world again!
Yeah!
What the heck was that?
It was so cool!
Go!
Oh, boy.
Let's do it!
Here's to the hunk!
Hey!
Listen up!
You guys are stiff as boards!
It's not like he's throwing knives out there!
Yes, sir!
He's looking at us!
Don't you dare interrupt my serve again, you squealing pigs.
Excuse me.
Could you please try to keep quiet while our team is serving?
Don't tell us what to do!
They do the same thing on TV, butt-face.
Damn it!
Weak, bro.
Shut up!
I think my serve toss went a little off to the side.
Azai!
Just focus on the ball!
Are they...
It sounds like they're booing.
Like, at the server.
For their server, it's all silence and concentration.
But for the other team, it's all noise and chaos.
Those guys have their fans well-trained.
Uh-oh!
Looks like the net caught that one, Phil.
All good.
Both teams are making strong serves as each tries to build momentum in the opening.
In this match, I think the one we'll really want to watch
is the player who's gained a reputation as Japan's number one high school setter,
Mr. Asumo Miya from Inarizaki.
Of course.
But I want to remind viewers that we should also keep an eye on the setter from Karasuna.
Tobio Kageyama from Karasuna High School.
Another promising setter and hopeful for the all-Japan youth team.
This is truly an East-West Setter Showdown.
Oh, shit!
I totally nailed that jump!
I forgot to hit the ball!
If you can't both jump and hit, then sit your ass down!
Did the little guy just say he forgot to hit the ball?
That's exactly what he said.
Are you saying the jumps we've seen so far aren't the highest he can go?
Is he really experimenting while he's playing against the tournament favorites?
I already knew Kageyama was the type to march to the beat of his own drum.
But I guess that kid's just as bad.
Let's wait.
That's why I'm going to do it.
There's no reason to do it.
I can't be able to do it.
We are.
I've lost power.
I can't be afraid.
I can't be able to do it.
Highly, highly, highly.
舞い上がれ
味わった
敗北の傷は
涙やって
花を咲かせる
諦めろと
笑えばいいさ
そんな言葉
僕は知らない
不可能と
笑えばいいさ
そんな言葉
僕は知らない